Abelson, Paul Additional Records 5807
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Paul Abelson Additional Records
1891-1948
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Abelson, Paul
5807
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
5710641
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 20, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5192: Paul Abelson Papers 5437 OH: Paul Abelson Interview Conducted by Jesse Carpenter 6165 mf: Paul Abelson Files on Microfilm
Arbitration, Industrial--New York (State)--New York.; Arbitration, Industrial--United States.; Abelson, Paul, 1878-1953; American Federation of Labor.; National War Labor Board.
5710641
- American Federation of Labor, 1893-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Anti-Union, 1909-1921 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Communism, 1918-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
- History, 1900-1934 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Labor Education, 1913-1936 (Box 1, Folder 10-14)
- Labor Relations - Wage Problem, 1922-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- National War Labor Board, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, memorandum, etc.
- National War Labor Board, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 18-24)
  Decisions/Press Releases.
- National War Labor Board, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Decisions
- National War Labor Board, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Second Regional Board Decisions
- National War Labor Board, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  Summaries of significant board actions
- National War Labor Board, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
  Policies, manuals, pamphlets
- National War Labor Board, 1942-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  miscellaneous reports, papers, articles, etc.
- National War Labor Board, 1942-1945 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
  MWLB newspaper clippings
- National War Labor Board, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  John B. Salternic Co. vs. United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers, Local 1225 and Stationary Engineers, Firemen, Maintenance and Building Service. Legal documents, arbitrator's notes, Routine correspondence, supporting documents.
- Reconstruction, 1891-1936 (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
- Socialism, 1902-1930 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
- Technological Changes, 1924-1938 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
- Trade Associations, 1910-1925 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- United States Labor, 1929-1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1930-1948 (Box 2, Folder 25-27)